Finding Aid for Kenneth C. Welch Papers 1915-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Michigan Projects
  - Michigan Planning and Development
    - Papers of the Seminar on the Dynamics of Urban Transportation, Detroit 1962 (Box 8)
      (8-4)
    - Reports concerning highways and transportation in Michigan 1947-1961 (Box 8)
      (8-5)
    - Michigan Society of Planning Officials
      - Newsletter 1947-1952 (Box 8)
        (8-6)
      - Correspondence 1947-1950 (Box 8)
        (8-7)
      - Community Planning Annual 1949-1952 (Box 8)
        (8-8)
    - Handbook and Directory of Planning in Michigan published by the American Institute of Planners 1955-1956 (Box 8)
      (8-9)
    - American Institute of Architects, Grand Valley Chapter
      - Handbook 1964 (Box 8)
        (8-10)
      - Minutes and Newsletters 1970-1971 (Box 8)
        (8-11)
    - A.I.A.--Miscellaneous papers 1947-1971 (Box 8)
      (8-12)
    - Michigan Society of Architects--Miscellaneous papers 1945-1958 (Box 8)
      (8-13)
    - Lake Michigan Region Planning Committee
      - Correspondence
        - 1960 (Box 8)
          (8-14)
        - 1961 (Box 8)
          (8-15)
        - January-August 1962 (Box 8)
          (8-16)
        - September-December 1962 (Box 8)
          (8-17)
        - 1963-1965 (Box 8)
          (8-18)
      - Minutes and Agendas
        - 1960 (Box 8)
          (8-19)
        - 1961 (Box 8)
          (8-20)
        - 1962-1965 (Box 8)
          (8-21)
      - Planning memos 1962-1972 (Box 8)
        (8-22)
      - News clippings and articles 1960-1962 (Box 8)
        (8-23)
      - Reports 1961-1963 (Box 8)
        (8-24)
      - Miscellaneous papers 1960-1964 (Box 8)
        (8-25)
    - A.I.A. Great Lakes District Seminars 1947 (Box 8)
      (8-26)
- Out-of-State Projects
  The Out-of-state project files are mainly shopping center design and development and include correspondence, reports, design documents and photographs. The files are most extensive for projects in Florida, Massachusetts, Ohio, and Texas.
  - Alabama, Russelville: Shopping Center Market Study 1963 (Box 9)
    (9-1)
  - Colorado, Denver
    - General Development Data 1954-1955 (Box 9)
      (9-2)
    - Coloden Moor Shopping Center
      - Correspondence 1948-1951 (Box 9)
        (9-3)
      - Economic Analysis (Box 9)
        (9-4)
    - Connecticut, West Hartford: Bishop's Corners-Description and Photographs 1954 (Box 9)
      (9-5)
  - Florida, Jacksonville
    - East and West Malls--Market Analysis 1957-1963 (Box 9)
      (9-6)
    - Winter Park Shopping Center--Market Analysis 1961 (Box 9)
      (9-7)
    - Beacon Hills and Harbor Shopping Center Building Plans 1960 (Box 9)
      (9-8)
    - Correspondence concerning miscellaneous Jacksonville project
      - January-September 1956 (Box 9)
        (9-9)
      - October-December 1956 (Box 9)
        (9-10)
      - January-June 1957 (Box 9)
        (9-11)
      - July-December 1957 (Box 9)
        (9-12)
      - January-June 1958 (Box 9)
        (9-13)
      - July 1958-March 1959 (Box 9)
        (9-14)
  - Illinois
    - Chicago
      - Yorktown Center 1968 (Box 9)
        (9-15)
      - Montgomery Ward Company 1957 (Box 9)
        (9-16)
    - Evanston
      - Fountain Square Planning Project (Box 9)
        (9-17)
    - Springfield
      - Springfield Center 1957 (Box 9)
        (9-18)
  - Indiana, Fort Wayne: Southtown mall 1966-1968 (Box 9)
    (9-19)
  - Iowa
    - Burlington: Town Market Analysis 1957 (Box 9)
      (9-20)
    - Des Moines: Grand Plaza Shopping Center
      - Miscellaneous papers 1959 (Box 9)
        (9-21)
    - Newton: Newton Shopping Center 1957 (Box 9)
      (9-22)
    - Spencer: Spencer Shopping Center 1957 (Box 9)
      (9-23)
  - Kentucky, Louisville
    - City Market Analysis for Community Research Inc. 1957 (Box 9)
      (9-24)
    - Correspondence, worksheets, sample aerials 1957 (Box 9)
      (9-25)
  - Maryland
    - Baltimore
      - Mondawmin Shopping Center
        - Reports 1955-1957, 2 folders (Box 9)
          (9-26; 9-27)
        - Miscellaneous papers (Box 9)
          (9-28)
    - Silver Springs: Market Study for Garfinckel's (Box 9)
      (9-29)
  - Massachusetts
    - Beverly: North Shore Shopping Center
      - Miscellaneous papers 1952 (Box 9)
        (9-30)
    - Boston: Boston Center Architects
      - Correspondence 1953-1954 (Box 9)
        (9-31)
      - Miscellaneous papers 1953-1954 (Box 9)
        (9-32)
    - Framingham: Shoppers' World
      - Correspondence 1948-1953 (Box 10)
        (10-1)
      - Reports (Box 10)
        (10-2)
      - Miscellaneous papers (Box 10)
        (10-3)
  - Minnesota, Edina: Southdale Shopping Center
    - Correspondence 1956-1958 (Box 10)
      (10-4)
    - News clippings and Promotion materials (Box 10)
      (10-5)
  - Missouri
    - Joplin: Normandy Shopping Center 1955 (Box 10)
      (10-6)
    - Kansas City
      - Meadowbrook Commercial Area Economic Study 1953 (Box 10)
        (10-7)
      - Hallmark Cards Inc.--Kansas City Real Estate Project Miscellaneous papers 1960 (Box 10)
        (10-8)
    - St. Louis County: St. Anne's Shopping Center (Box 10)
      (10-9)
  - Nebraska
    - Omaha: "The Center" 1954 (Box 10)
      (10-10)
    - Correspondence concerning miscellaneous Nebraska projects
      - July-December 1952 (Box 10)
        (10-11)
      - January-June 1953 (Box 10)
        (10-12)
      - July-December 1953 (Box 10)
        (10-13)
      - 1958-1961 (Box 10)
        (10-14)
  - New Jersey, Camden: Market Analysis of the Big H for Webb and Knapp, Inc. 1952 (Box 10)
    (10-15)
  - New Mexico, Albuquerque: The Albuquerque Office Building 1965
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 10)
      (10-16)
  - New York City
    - Flushing Central Business District Study (Box 10)
      (10-17)
    - R.H. Macy Company--Parkchester Data 1943 (Box 10)
      (10-18)
  - North Carolina
    - Charlotte: Charlottetown Mall
      - News clippings 1959 (Box 10)
        (10-19)
    - Wilmington: Hanover Shopping Center
      - Correspondence October 1959-June 1960 (Box 10)
        (10-20)
      - October 1960-May 1965 (Box 10)
        (10-21)
  - Ohio
    - Dayton
      - Hills and Dales Shopping Center 1956 (Box 10)
        (10-22)
      - Fairmont Shopping Plaza 1956 (Box 10)
        (10-23)
    - Toledo
      - Secor-Central Shopping Center (Box 10)
        (10-24)
      - Stover Field Shopping Center (Box 10)
        (10-25)
    - West Lucas County: Economic Analysis for Zoning Study 1961 (Box 10)
      (10-26)
    - Papers concerning miscellaneous Ohio projects 1961 (Box 10)
      (10-27)
  - Pennsylvania
    - Pittsburgh
      - Commercial Area Studies 1945, 1954 (Box 11)
        (11-1)
      - St. Clair Shopping Center (Box 11)
        (11-2)
    - St. David's: District Shopping Center
      - Correspondence 1954-1960 (Box 11)
        (11-3)
      - Market Analysis (Box 11)
        (11-4)
  - Texas
    - Austin: Market Studies (Box 11)
      (11-5)
    - El Paso
      - Airport Village Shopping Center 1955
        - Miscellaneous papers (Box 11)
          (11-6)
      - Texas Homes Apartments 1962 (Box 11)
        (11-7)
    - San Antonio
      - General Economic Studies 1957-1958 (Box 11)
        (11-8)
      - North Star Mall
        - Economic Survey 1958 (Box 11)
          (11-9)
    - Correspondence concerning miscellaneous Texas Projects
      - March-December 1957 (Box 11)
        (11-10)
      - January-June 1958 (Box 11)
        (11-11)
      - July 1958-April 1968 (Box 11)
        (11-12)
  - Virginia, Norfolk: Norfolk Redevelopment and Housing Authority, Miscellaneous papers 1961 (Box 11)
    (11-13)
  - Washington, D.C.: Spring Valley Shopping Center 1956 (Box 11)
    (11-14)
  - Wisconsin
    - Madison: University of Wisconsin parking plan (Box 11)
      (11-15)
    - Milwaukee: Economic Survey for Wamben Realty Co. (Box 11)
      (11-16)
  - Venezuela, Caracas: Commercial Center--Sabana Grande Project 1951-1952 (Box 11)
    (11-17)
- Articles and Speeches 1938-1967
  Articles and speeches deal mainly with topics relating to the design of commercial and retail space and were published in a variety of professional and trade magazines or presented before professional meetings such as the American Institute of Architects and the Illuminating Engineering Society. The series is arranged chronologically.
  - 1938
    - "Merchandising Goes Modern"--Address: Indianapolis September 1938 (Box 12)
      (12-1)
  - 1942
    - "Modernizing for Wartime Efficiency" Apparel Arts, March 1942 (Box 12)
      (12-2)
  - 1943
    - "Post-War Pattern for Commercial Building" American Builder, June 1943 (Box 12)
      (12-3)
    - "Self Selection is Sensible" Apparel Arts, October 1943 (Box 12)
      (12-4)
  - 1944
    - Address to the Michigan Society of Architects, Detroit Chapter Conference on Planning-- February 16, 1944 (Box 12)
      (12-5)
    - "Where are Department Stores Going?" Architectural Record, November 1944 (Box 12)
      (12-6)
    - Address: Illuminating Engineering Society Technical Conference September 15, 1944 (Box 12)
      (12-7)
    - "Modern Trends in Department Store Planning" Department Store Economist, November 1944 (Box 12)
      (12-8)
    - "Your Store Tomorrow" Women's Wear Daily, December 27-28, 1944 (Box 12)
      (12-9)
    - "Some Economics of Store Lighting" Illuminating Engineering, December 1944 (Box 12)
      (12-10)
  - 1945
    - Address: Illuminating Engineering Society, Cleveland January 15, 1945 (Box 12)
      (12-11)
    - "Postwar Store Planning"--Address: Canadian Retail Federation, Toronto January 17, 1945 (Box 12)
      (12-12)
    - "Grand Rapids Parking Plan" Architectural Record, February 1945 (Box 12)
      (12-13)
    - "Modern Store Arrangement and Civic Planning"--Address: Lawrence and Emporia, Kansas July 10, 1945-July 11, 1945 (Box 12)
      (12-14)
    - "Modern Lighting and Store Operation" Lighting and Lamps, February 1945 (Box 12)
      (12-15)
  - 1946
    - "Reflection Factors in Store Windows" Architectural Engineering Magazine, July 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-16)
    - "Post-War Hat Selling", Hat Life 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-17)
    - "Lightness and Brightness for Selling" Illuminating Engineering, May 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-18)
    - "Applied Brightness Control in Schools" Architectural Record, March 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-19)
    - "Store Modernization and Display" Address--Michigan Retail Dry Goods Association June 6, 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-20)
    - "Store Lighting" Hat Life, June 1946, December 1946, January 1947 (Box 12)
      (12-21)
    - "Living and Shopping" American Druggist, July 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-22)
    - "New Concepts in Store Lighting" Architectural Record, August 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-23)
    - "Neighborhood Shopping Centers and Parking Problems" Address: Planning Institute, Grand Rapids September 4, 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-24)
    - "Modernize for Prestige and Sales"--Address: National Stationers' Convention September 30, 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-25)
    - Address: New England Clothiers and Furnishers Association November 12, 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-26)
    - "Vision and Selling" Curtain and Drapery Magazine, November 1946, December 1946, January 1947 (Box 12)
      (12-27)
    - "Convenience vs. Shopping Goods" Women's Wear Daily, December 26, 1946 (Box 12)
      (12-28)
  - 1947
    - "Automobiles, Cities and Shopping Centers"--Address: Snag Club February 25, 1947 (Box 12)
      (12-29)
    - "Display and Lighting" Display World, August 1947 (Box 12)
      (12-30)
    - "The Department Store" Forms and Functions of Twentieth Century Architecture, Columbia University, 1947 (Box 12)
      (12-31)
  - 1948
    - "Design of the Modern Store with Emphasis on Lighting and Color" Address: Electric Institute of Boston January 15, 1948 (Box 12)
      (12-32)
    - "Effect of Retail Distribution on City Plan" Michigan Society of Architects February 24, 1948 (Box 12)
      (12-33)
    - "Planned Flexibility Essential" Women's Wear Daily, February 25, 1948 (Box 12)
      (12-34)
    - Store Modernization--Clinics and Forums (transcript) 1948 (Box 12)
      (12-35)
    - "The Relocation of Commercial Areas"--Address: National Planning Conference of the American Society of Planning Officials, New York October 13, 1948 (Box 12)
      (12-36)
    - "Brightness Engineering" Architectural Forum, May 1948 (Box 12)
      (12-37)
    - "Regional Suburban Centers"--Address: American Institute of Planners Meeting, Long Beach, Cal. 1948 (Box 12)
      (12-38)
  - 1949
    - "A Method of Analyzing Economics of Store Lighting" Illuminating Engineering, January 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-39)
    - "Light and Color Treatment as Applied to Unusual Interiors" Address: Rochester Chapter IES February 10, 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-40)
    - Address: 7th Ann Arbor Conference, April 1 and 2 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-41)
    - "Markets in the Meadows" Forum, March 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-42)
    - "Store Lighting Economics"--Address: Western Regional Conference of the IES, San Francisco March 3, 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-43)
    - "Modern Shopping Centers"--Address: National Citizens Conference on Community Planning, Oklahoma City March 28, 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-44)
    - "Principles of Store Lighting and their Proper Application" Address: Milwaukee IES Chapter Conference May 19, 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-45)
    - "The Modern Shopping Center" Tennessee Planner, August 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-46)
    - "A Store Front--Siegells" Architectural Record, October 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-47)
    - "The Design of Stores, Planning and Lighting"--Address: AIA Regional Convention, St. Louis November 19, 1949 (Box 12)
      (12-48)
  - 1950
    - "Flextures" Architectural Forum, February 1950 (Box 12)
      (12-49)
    - "New Shopping Trends"--Address: National Institute of Cleaning and Dyeing March 14, 1950 (Box 12)
      (12-50)
    - "What is the Future of the Shopping Center" April 1950 (Box 12)
      (12-51)
    - "What Makes a 1940 Store Obsolete?" Forum, August 1950 (Box 12)
      (12-52)
    - "Sub-Central Regional Retail Districts" November 16, 1950 (Box 12)
      (12-53)
  - 1951
    - "New Regional Shopping Centers"--Ann Arbor Conference 1951 (Box 12)
      (12-54)
    - "Current Relocation of Retail Centers"--AIA Wisconsin Second Annual Convention, Milwaukee February 16, 1951 (Box 12)
      (12-55)
    - "Regional Shopping Centers" Architectural Record, March 1951 (Box 12)
      (12-56)
    - "Location and Design of Shopping Centers"--Address: American Planning and Civic Association, Miami April 3, 1951 (Box 12)
      (12-57)
  - 1952
    - "Shopping Centers" (Review) Progressive Architecture, March 1952 (Box 12)
      (12-58)
    - "Crossroads in Architecture"--Symposium, Museum of Modern Art June 24, 1952 (Box 12)
      (12-59)
  - 1953
    - "Relationship of Marketing Studies to Highway Access and Traffic Facilities of Large Regional Centers"--32nd Annual Meeting of the Highway Research Board, Washington, D.C. January 13, 1953 (Box 12)
      (12-60)
    - "Low Cost Electric Lighting" Architectural Forum, October 1953 (Box 12)
      (12-61)
  - 1956
    - "Types and Architectural Concepts of Shopping Centers Women's Wear Daily October 1956 (Box 12)
      (12-62)
  - 1957
    - "Formula Predetermines Site Potential" Daily News Record, March 22, 1957 (Box 12)
      (12-63)
    - "Shopping Center Trends"--Text for General Shopping Center Book (Box 12)
      (12-64)
  - 1958
    - "Regional Center and Downtown" May 1958 (Box 12)
      (12-65)
  - 1967
    - "The Architectural Discipline of Lighting" Architectural Discipline, August 1967 (Box 12)
      (12-66)
  - Undated
    - "A Case for the Two Level Regional Center" (Box 12)
      (12-67)
    - "The Regional Center and Downtown" (Box 12)
      (12-68)
    - Miscellaneous writings about lighting (Box 12)
      (12-69)
    - Miscellaneous writings about shopping centers (Box 12)
      (12-70 and 12-71)
    - Miscellaneous writings about traffic and parking (Box 12)
      (12-72)
    - Miscellaneous writings about urban planning (Box 12)
      (12-73)
  - Articles about Kenneth C. Welch's work (Box 12)
    (12-74)
- Photographs
  The photographs series is divided into six subseries: Michigan projects, Regional, Out-of-state projects, Miscellaneous photographs, Miscellaneous albums, Outsize photographs. Included are images of Welch's architectural projects throughout the United States, especially shopping centers, including Northland (Southfield, Michigan) and Breton Village (Grand Rapids, Michigan). There are also photographs of a variety of projects in Grand Rapids, Michigan, including photos of downtown buildings and streets and Fountain Street Church. In addition, this series has photographic studies of downtown and shopping center businesses in various cities; and aerial photos of several Michigan localities.
  - Michigan projects
    - Detroit
      - Aerial photographs circa 1944 (Box 13)
      - Northland Shopping Center circa 1955 (Box 15)
    - East Lansing, Central business district study circa 1960 (Box 13)
      (includes photos of stores and street party)
    - Flint, Aerial photographs circa 1960 (Box 13)
    - Grand Haven, Temporary shopping mall 1960 (Box 13)
    - Grand Rapids--Buildings
      - Central Reformed Church, Lighting design 1960s (Box 13)
        (interior views)
      - Fountain Street Church, Lighting design circa 1965-1968
        - Exteriors (Box 13)
        - Interiors, 2 folders (Box 13)
          (includes photos of worship services and appearances of Duke Ellington and Ella Fitzgerald)
      - Church of the Nazarene 1960s (Box 13)
        (exterior and interior views of several buildings)
      - Reed's Lake Apartments circa 1967-1968 (Box 13)
        (includes photos of Reeds Lake and adjacent parkland)
      - Breton Village Shopping Center circa 1968-1970, 3 folders (Box 13)
        (includes photos of other Grand Rapids area shopping centers)
      - Kenneth C. Welch residence (Box 13)
        (chiefly aerial photos of vicinity)
      - Kent Country Club 1963 (Box 13)
    - Grand Rapids--Planning
      - Grand Rapids parking plan 1940s (Box 13)
        (includes downtown views)
      - Aerial photographs 1954, undated
        - Prints (Box 13)
        - Negatives (Box 13)
      - Central business district, late 1950s (Box 13)
        (includes street scenes)
      - Kent County Planning Commission, Aerial photographs circa 1960, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Kalamazoo, "Downtown Kalamazoo's Mall" circa 1960 (Box 13)
    - Lansing, Downtown Rehabilitation Program circa 1960 (Box 13)
    - Owosso (aerial views) undated (Box 13)
    - Plainwell, Public Library expansion circa 1965 (Box 13)
    - Sparta, Public Library expansion project circa 1960 (Box 13)
      (includes exteriors, interiors, and construction photos)
    - Spring Lake circa 1965 (Box 13)
      (includes street scenes and aerial photos)
    - Whitehall 1951 (Box 13)
      (exteriors and interiors of schools)
  - Regional
    - Lake Michigan Regional Planning Committee 1960s (Box 13)
      (includes photos of meetings and aerial photos of Chicago area)
  - Out-of-state projects
    - Colorado, Denver, Aerial photographs undated (Box 13)
    - Connecticut, West Hartford, Bishop's Corners (Box 13)
      (photos located in Box 9)
    - Florida
      - Jacksonville, Aerial photographs 1962 (Box 13)
      - Other locations 1960s (Box 15)
        (comparative shopping center photos)
    - Iowa, Des Moines, Grand Plaza Shopping Center circa 1959 (Box 13)
    - Maryland
      - Baltimore, Mondawmin Shopping Center circa 1955 (Box 13)
      - Glen Burnie, Harundale Mall 1958 (Box 15)
    - Massachusetts
      - Beverly, North Shore Shopping Center 1947, undated (Box 13)
      - Framingham, Shoppers' World 1951, 1954, undated (Box 13)
        (includes photos of flood)
    - Minnesota, Edina, Southdale Shopping Center circa 1956 (Box 13)
    - New Mexico, Albuquerque, The Albuquerque Office Building circa 1965 (Box 13)
      (chiefly aerial photos)
    - New York, New York City
      - Port Authority Bus System terminal 1955 (Box 15)
      - Flushing central business district study 1953 (Box 15)
      - Yonkers Cross Country Shopping Center 1955 (Box 15)
    - North Carolina
      - Charlotte, Charlottetown Mall 1961, undated (Box 13)
      - Wilmington, Hanover Shopping Center 1963-1964, undated (Box 15)
    - Pennsylvania, St. David's, District Shopping Center circa 1956 (Box 13)
    - Texas
      - El Paso, Airport Village Shopping Center circa 1955 (Box 13)
      - San Antonio, North Star Mall circa 1958 (Box 13)
    - Wisconsin, Wausau, Aerial photographs undated (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous photographs
    - Architectural, 2 folders (Box 13)
      (also 1 folder located in oversize Box 15)
    - Personal (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous albums
    (include mixture of identified and unidentified photos)
    - Omaha, Neb., Whitefish Bay, Wis., Miami (Box 14)
    - Montrose County, Md. (Box 15)
    - Italy (Box 14)
    - "Shopping Centers" (Box 14)
    - Baltimore, Md., and other shopping centers (Box 14)
    - Baltimore, Md., New York City, and other areas (Box 15)
  - Outsize photographs
    - Michigan projects: Detroit, Northland Shopping Center circa 1955 (Box 15)
    - Out-of-state projects
      - Florida, Other locations 1960s (Box 15)
      - Maryland, Glen Burnie, Harundale Mall 1958 (Box 15)
      - New York, New York City
        - Port Authority Bus System terminal 1955 (Box 15)
        - Flushing central business district study 1953 (Box 15)
        - Yonkers Cross Country Shopping Center 1955 (Box 15)
      - North Carolina
        - Wilmington, Hanover Shopping Center 1963-1964, undated (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous photographs
      - Architectural (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous albums
      - Montrose County, Md. (Box 15)
      - Baltimore, Md., New York City, and other areas (Box 15)